VIVEKANAND JHA

A/5 Tikri Kalan ext. Near Kabir park Nangloi New Delhi-110041

Mail id:-vjha1884@gmail.com

Mob.-9871416659



OBJECTIVE

Having More than 8 Years' Experience in Sales & Marketing, Key Account Management, Retention Management, Pre Sales, Business Development, Team Management, Customer Handling & Interaction with the Clients .To build a career as a Sales Manager and work in an organization which will give ample amount of opportunity for growth. I intend to contribute effectively and effeciently in the growth of an organization

WORK EXPERIENCE

- Working in DIGITAL MANTRA PVT LTD As a KEY ACCOUNT MANAGER
 From June 2017
- JOB RESPONSIBILITY-:
- Accountable for developing, maximizing and maintaining long term
 relationship with potential and existing clients in order to enhance customer
 satisfaction, customer retention, and company sales. Assessed the types of
 services and products the clients need in order to ensure their satisfaction.
 Prepared reports on market analysis, competitor analysis, and market trends.
 Managed and provided assistance in managing and maintaining accounts of
 strategic clients
- Heading Team of 4 Front Line Managers.
- Achieving Sales Target.
- Prepared reports for management as required.
- Preparing Business Plan for the Team.
- Interacting with the Clients on a continuous basis regarding the specifications of the projects, handling their queries.

- Keeping the customer updated about the status of the projects through live chats, e-mails and phones.
- Tracking of the project and sending Status reports to the customers.
- Explain to customers how specific types of Promotion will help promote their products or services in the most effective way possible
- To Provide Training to new joiners
- Worked in INFOCOM NETWORK LTD (TRADEINDIA.COM) As a Sr. Executive Key Account, From October 2014 to May 2017.
- Started Working as a Sr. Executive Key Account (Retention)
- Got promoted as a Key Account Manager (Retention)

• JOB RESPONSIBILITY-:

- Utilizing Business Intelligence to identify existing accounts with growth opportunity and distribute appropriately to sales representatives while focusing on targeted customer penetration strategies
- Creating and managing an account database to report on account growth, penetration and retention
- Working with the Inside Team Sales Manager and representatives to secure large or complex contracts; prepare ROI's, contracts, contract review forms and contract summary forms as needed
- Utilizing sales reporting, call data, and quality assurance observations to deliver timely and effective feedback, coaching and training for performance goals and operations metrics to ensure that associates are meeting standards
- Acting as the point of contact and resolution for customer escalations
- To know the services Bought by customer & give presentation As per the needs of customer
- Explain to customers how specific types of Promotion will help promote their products or services in the most effective way possible

- Worked In CEASEFIRE INDUSTRIES LTD As a Business Development Manager From 3rd September 2012 to September 2014.
- Started Working as a Business Development Management Manager in September
 2012

- Got promoted as a Sr. Business Development Management Manager June 2013
- Got promoted as a Sr. Territory Manager in 2014

JOB RESPONSIBILITY-:

- Dealing with Clients as per business requirement.
- Cold Calling, Lead Generation, Gathering Sales Intelligence, Handling Objections and Account Management.
- Business-to-Business lead generation and setting appointments
- Re-qualifying leads from events, mailers, other activities.
- Calling mid-large size organizations.
- Effective communication of leads reports and action items to Sales & Marketing teams. Independently monitor progress of Marketing-generated leads track, analyze, interpret and report results.
- Responsible for meeting or exceeding monthly metrics such as setting appointments, lead conversions and identifying new prospects.
- Identify and resolve issues and conflicts within the project team..
- Develop best practices and tools for project execution and management.

ACADEMIC QUALIFICATION

- Passed PGDM from DSPSR in session 2010-2012.(Marketing) 1st Division
- B.A (Hons) History from "University of Delhi" from Ram Lal Anad College
- 12TH passed from BIEC with science stream (PCB) 1st division
- 10TH passed from BSEB (2nd Division)

PROFFESIONAL QUALIFICATION

Done Fundamental Course of computer from NIIT (Delhi)

Done PGDM from DSPSR in session 2010-2012. (Marketing)

- Won third prize in quiz competition organized by ITS, Mohan Nagar on 19th August, 2010.
- Member of NGO, Working as a secretary since 2006 in Tikri kalan Well Fare Association

❖ Personal details

NAME : VIVEKANAND JHA FATHERS NAME : Mr. Shreedhar Jha

Language known : English, Hindi, Sanskrit..

Permanent Address

A-5, Tikri kalan Extn.

Near Kabir Park, Nangloi, New Delhi-41

Declaration

I hereby declare that the all statements made in this application are true, complete and correct to the best of my knowledge and belief.

Date : 15.05.2021 Place : Delhi